<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">ALL 4 OCEAN</string>

    <string name="curiosidade">THERE ARE LAKES AND RIVERS BELOW THE OCEAN SURFACE Some surfaces in the ocean present views that don\'t seem to make any logical sense – rivers and lakes, some of them kilometers long, can extend across the sea floor even though they are submerged. How can a body of water exist within a body of water? Seafloor water seeps in and dissolves salt layers, forming depressions. Since the water in the depression is denser than the water around it, it settles into the depression and forms a distinct pool.</string>
    <string name="voce_sabia">Did You Know?</string>
    <string name="come_ar">Start</string>
    <string name="vamos_atualizar_o_seu_cadastro">Let\'s update your Registration</string>
    <string name="nome">Name</string>
    <string name="telefone">Phone</string>
    <string name="salvar">Save</string>
    <string name="como_eu_posso_ajudar">How Can I Help?</string>
    <string name="informacoes_como_ajudar">Here are some ways to help the Blue Economy:\n\n1. Reduce the use of disposable plastic.\n\n2. Participate in coastal cleanup initiatives.\n\n3. Support sustainable companies and products.\n\n4. Educate yourself about the oceans and their importance to the planet.\n\n5. Contribute to marine conservation organizations.\n\n6. Practice sustainable fishing.\n\n7. Raise awareness about the importance of oceans for life on Earth.</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="buscar">Search</string>
    <string name="atulizar_cadastro">Update Registration</string>
    <string name="email">Email</string>
    <string name="senha">Password</string>
    <string name="confirmacao_senha">Confirm Password</string>
    <string name="cadastrar">Register</string>
    <string name="voltar">Back</string>
    <string name="_25_curiosidades_sobre_os_oceanos">25 CURIOSITIES ABOUT THE OCEANS</string>
    <string name="Curiosidade">Curiosity</string>
    <string name="sobre">About</string>
    <string name="ajudar">Help</string>
    <string name="sair">Exit</string>
    <string name="ajude_a_cuidar_dos_nossos_oceanos">Help take care of our oceans!!</string>
    <string name="bem_vindo">Welcome</string>
    <string name="esqueci_a_senha">Forgot Password</string>
    <string name="entrar">Log In</string>
    <string name="enviar">Send</string>
    <string name="projeto_all4ocean">Project: All4Ocean</string>
    <string name="economia_azul_informa">Blue Economy: Information about the Blue Economy here…</string>
    <string name="preencha_todos_os_campos">Fill in all fields!!</string>
    <string name="email_invalido">Invalid email!!</string>
    <string name="email_exemplo">Email example: user@gmail.com</string>
    <string name="senhas_diferentes">The passwords must match!!</string>
    <string name="senha_curta">The password must be at least 6 characters long</string>
    <string name="cadastro_sucesso">Registration Successful</string>
    <string name="usuario_cadastrado">User already registered</string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_texto">curiosity_text</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_titulo">curiosity_title</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_1">Curiosity 1: The oceans cover 71% of the Earth s surface.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_2">Curiosity 2: Most of the life on Earth is in the oceans.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_3">Curiosity 3: The oceans produce over 50% of the planet s oxygen.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_4">Curiosity 4: There are more historical artifacts submerged in the sea than in all the museums of the world.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_5">Curiosity 5: The largest animal in the world, the blue whale, lives in the oceans.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_6">Curiosity 6: Less than 5% of the world\'s oceans have been explored.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_7">Curiosity 7: Ocean currents transport heat around the globe.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_8">Curiosity 8: Coral reefs are known as the rainforests of the sea.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_9">Curiosity 9: The ocean contains over 20 million tons of gold.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_10">Curiosity 10: The Mariana Trench is the deepest point in the oceans.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_11">Curiosity 11: The temperature of seawater can influence global climate.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_12">Curiosity 12: The world\'s longest mountain range is submerged in the ocean.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_13">Curiosity 13: Jellyfish are some of the oldest organisms on the planet.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_14">Curiosity 14: Sound travels five times faster in water than in air.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_15">Curiosity 15: There are underwater lakes and rivers in the oceans.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_16">Curiosity 16: The ocean harbors over 90% of the available habitat for life.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_17">Curiosity 17: Tsunamis are giant waves caused by underwater earthquakes.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_18">Curiosity 18: The Arctic sea ice layer is diminishing.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_19">Curiosity 19: The manatee, a marine mammal, is known as the sea cow.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_20">Curiosity 20: There are active underwater volcanoes.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_21">Curiosity 21: Ocean waters are composed of 3.5% salt.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_22">Curiosity 22: The ocean has an incredible and still unknown biodiversity.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_23">Curiosity 23: Krill, a small crustacean, serves as a cornerstone in the marine food chain.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_24">Curiosity 24: Waves are primarily caused by wind.</string>
    <string name="curiosidade_25">Curiosity 25: The sea plays a crucial role in the water cycle.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_1">Curiosity 1 Detail: The oceans are not evenly distributed, with most of the water concentrated in the southern hemisphere.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_2">Curiosity 2 Detail: About 94% of the planet\'s species of life are aquatic.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_3">Curiosity 3 Detail: Phytoplankton in the oceans are responsible for much of the oxygen production.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_4">Curiosity 4 Detail: The oceans are a vast repository of history, with many shipwrecks and submerged ruins.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_5">Curiosity 5 Detail: Blue whales can grow up to 30 meters long and weigh up to 200 tons.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_6">Curiosity 6 Detail: Ocean exploration is limited by its extreme depth and pressure.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_7">Curiosity 7 Detail: Ocean currents are driven by wind and the rotation of the Earth.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_8">Curiosity 8 Detail: Coral reefs harbor about 25% of all marine life.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_9">Curiosity 9 Detail: Gold is dissolved in seawater in small concentrations.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_10">Curiosity 10 Detail: The Mariana Trench has a depth of about 11,034 meters.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_11">Curiosity 11 Detail: Phenomena like El Niño and La Niña are examples of how water temperature influences climate.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_12">Curiosity 12 Detail: The Mid-Atlantic Ridge is a submerged mountain range that stretches for about 65,000 km.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_13">Curiosity 13 Detail: Jellyfish have existed for over 500 million years.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_14">Curiosity 14 Detail: Sound propagates faster in water due to its density.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_15">Curiosity 15 Detail: Underwater lakes and rivers are formed by differences in salinity.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_16">Curiosity 16 Detail: The oceans provide the largest continuous habitat on Earth.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_17">Curiosity 17 Detail: Tsunamis can devastate coastal areas when they reach land.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_18">Curiosity 18 Detail: The reduction of sea ice affects the habitat of Arctic species.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_19">Curiosity 19 Detail: The manatee is a herbivore that lives in shallow coastal waters and rivers.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_20">Curiosity 20 Detail: Underwater volcanoes can form new islands when they erupt.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_21">Curiosity 21 Detail: The salt in the oceans comes from the erosion of terrestrial rocks.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_22">Curiosity 22 Detail: New marine species are constantly being discovered.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_23">Curiosity 23 Detail: Krill are vital for many marine species, including whales and penguins.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_24">Curiosity 24 Detail: Wind energy transferred to the ocean surface generates waves.</string>
    <string name="detalhe_curiosidade_25">Curiosity 25 Detail: The ocean is essential in the water cycle, including evaporation and precipitation.</string>
    <string name="email_ou_senha_invalidos">Invalid email or password</string>
    <string name="projeto_info">Project: All4Ocean\n\nAll4Ocean is an application developed to raise awareness and protect the oceans. Our goal is to educate people about the importance of the oceans and encourage actions to preserve the marine environment.</string>
    <string name="economia_azul_info">Blue Economy:\n\nThe Blue Economy refers to all economic activities related to the oceans and seas. It includes sectors such as fishing, tourism, maritime transport, oceanic renewable energy, among others.</string>

</resources>